Sergei laskevich

E-mail: jaskiewiczs@icloud.com, GitHub: github.com/broadwaylamb

Active open source contributor with infinite amount of love and passion for compilers and programming languages, non-trivial commits to the Swift compiler and standard library, 4 years of iOS development experience, excellent knowledge of Swift, good knowledge of C/C++, Rust, Objective-C and Haskell, and mathematical background. Always pursuing quality.

Work experience

PERIOD Aug 2019 - present

ROLE C/C++ Developer (LLVM toolchains), Access Softek

PERIOD Jun 2019 - present

ROLE OpenCombine open source project maintainer

- Implemented an open-source version of Combine— a reactive framework for processing values over time, developed by Apple.
- Thorough test coverage
- >600 stars on GitHub

https://github.com/broadwaylamb/OpenCombine

PERIOD Jan 2017 - present

ROLE Swift open source project contributor

- Implemented user-facing compiler diagnostics and flags
- Fixed bugs in the standard library

https://github.com/apple/swift

http://github.com/apple/swift-corelibs-foundation

PERIOD Jul 2017 - Oct 2018

ROLE iOS Developer, iD EAST

Developed a trading app for Bank Otkritie – Otkritie Broker.

Otkritie Broker lets you track state of your broker accounts on convenient charts, transfer your assets, perform trading operations online, and much more.

Otkritie Broker is a secure, modern looking and carefully designed application, Tagline Awards 2018 winner, Top-200 Finance in App Store.

App Store link: https://apple.co/2YE6N5H

- Designed the architecture, UI, business logic and security from ground up
- Set up continuous integration
- Reviewied team members' code, ensuring its highest quality and absence of vulnerabilities.
- Core technologies: Swift, Moya/Alamofire, WebSockets, Firebase

Education

PERIOD 2014 - 2018

B. Sc. in mathematics and mechanics, Saint Petersburg State University

PERIOD Sep 2018 - present

Computer Science Center Student

Computer Science Center is a joint initiative of JetBrains, Computer Science Club (based at St. Petersburg Department of Steklov Mathematical Institute), and The Yandex School of Data Analysis. It includes programming and math evening courses, as well as practices under supervision of experienced scientists and developers.

Professional skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Swift (4 years of experience, including maintenance of open source libraries, Swift compiler and standard library contributions)

C/C++ (1 year of in-depth learning at Computer Science Center, with 'excellent' grade; contributions to an LLVM-targeted compiler)

Rust (1 semester of in-depth learning at Computer Science Center, taught by Alexey Kladov, one of the most active contributors to the language, with 'excellent' grade)

Objective-C (ported a styling library to Swift)

Haskell (1 semester of functional programming course at Computer Science Center, with 'excellent' grade)

Basic experience with Python and OCaml

OTHER EXPERIENCE & SKILLS Respectful team member and code reviewer; active user of command line and automation tools, wrote such tools myself, including:

- LLVM docset generator for Dash app (https://github.com/broadwaylamb/generate-llvm-docset)
- Swift snapshot downloader (https://github.com/broadwaylamb/SwiftSnapshotDownloader)

PROFESSIONAL INTERESTS LLVM, compilers, type theory, operating systems, programming languages, reverse engineering, fuzzers, low-level programming, functional programming